TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
먹고 말겠어!
I'll eat you!
괴물 때문에!
That monster!
그랬구나...
I see now...
이, 이건...
W- what the...?
허니 구출 대작전
Operation Rescue Honey
(en: The Bee Rescues the Honey)
기간 한정! 메다로트 파트 수리, 지금 100엔 대 캠페인!
Time limited! Medarot Parts Repair is now only 100 yens!
데스 메다로트는 거절이야!
We don't accept Death Medarots!
최근 손님이 적으니까 단념하고 시작한 건데...
We began doing this because there wasn't enough customers recently...
이렇게 의뢰가 쌓이다니...
but look at all the requests...
으쌰으쌰!
Only a mountain more to go!
200엔으로 할 걸 그랬어.
Maybe I should make it 200 yens...
-나에 씨!
-어?
-Ms. Nae!
-Hm?
이거 3번가의 스기노모리 것이지? 배달하러 다녀올게.
This is for Suginomori at the 3rd street, right? I'll go deliver.
부탁해.
Please do.
그러니까 손을 놓으면 안 된다고 했잖아.
I told you you shouldn't let your balloon go.
그래도...
But...
저런.
Oh my.
잠깐만 기다려.
Just a moment.
이랴.
Here we go.
여기.
Here it is!
떨어뜨릴게.
I'm dropping this.
고마워, 메다로트 언니!
Thank you, Medarot sister!
그래.
No problem.
자, 배달, 배달.
Now, delivery, delivery.
응?
Huh?
봤겠다!
You saw me!
나에 씨! 메타비 비행 파트 수리 끝났어?
Ms. Nae! Is Metabee's flight parts' repair done?
끝났어. 허니?
It's finished. Honey?
심부름 갔었어. 미안. 저 산더미에 있는데 찾아 줄래?
She went for an errand. Sorry. Find yours in that mountain of parts.
-어!
-Right!
어! 이게 더 멋져! 이거 가져가자!
Hey! This looks way cooler! Let's take this!
가져가자니 너 그거 도둑질이야!
Take? Hey, do you even know you're a thief if you do that?
-농담이야, 당연히! 진지빨지 마!
-센스 없는 농담을 한 게 나쁜 거야!
-It's a joke, obviously! Don't be serious out of nowhere!
-You're the one to blame for making a stupid joke!
-늦네. 뭐 하고 있을까, 허니는?
-뭐!? 이게 건방지게!
-건방진 건 네 낯짝이다!
-She's late. What is Honey doing?
-What!? How impudent of you!
-Your face is impudent!
-내 얼굴 어디가-
-네 얼굴뿐만이 아니라 몸까지 이렇게 이렇게-
-What about my face is-
-Not only your face but also is your body so-
너 겁나 잘 늘어나잖아?
Aren't you so stretchable!?
-이게, 이게-
-저기...
-How dare you!
-Excuse me...
어, 스기노모리 군.
Hey, Suginomori.
내 파트 수리 끝났어요?
Is my part repaired?
어?
What?
뭔 짓이야? 그만해! 여기서 꺼내줘!
What are you doing!? Stop it! Let me out of here!
징징대지 않아도 지금 자유롭게 해 줄 거야! 네 기억을 지운 다음에 말야.
You don't have to cry to ask me - I am going to do that! After erasing your memory, that is.
그, 그만해!
S- stop it!
에잇, 데스 메다로트용 플러그는 안 맞는구나.
Eh, this plug is for Death Medarot and isn't fitting.
허니는 한참 아까 나갔어.
Honey went out a while ago.
그런데 아직 스기노모리 군 집이 아니라니...
And she's not at Suginomori's house yet?
어디서 한눈팔고 있는 거 아니야?
Isn't she just wandering off somewhere?
허니는 그런 제멋대로인 아이가 아니야.
Honey isn't that irresponsible.
잇키하고는 달라.
She isn't like Ikki.
또 그 소리냐!
You're saying that again!?
어!
Hey!
이게 내 꺼!
This is mine!
그렇네. 왜 이런 곳에...
You're right. Why is this even here?
가져가도 돼요?
Can I take this with me?
그래, 그래도 돼.
Yes, you can.
다행이에요. 고마워요!
That's good to hear! Thank you!
조심해!
Be careful!
그 말은...
That means...
허니는 여기서?
Honey disappeared at here?
저기, 묻고 싶은 게 있어.
Hey, I'd like to ask you something.
뭐, 뭐야!
W- what is it!?
내 허니 못 봤어?
Have you seen my Honey?
모, 모, 몰라!
N- n- no idea!
나, 나, 시간 없어!
I- I'm in hurry!
정말 속 다 보이는 놈이야.
Everything about him is obvious.
콧구멍까지 부풀어서 말야.
His nostrils were swelling out.
자, 뒤쫓자.
Let's chase him.
메다로트용 플러그 가져 왔어.
Now I'm with a plug for Medarot.
이번이야말로 네가 본 걸 전부 잊게 해 주겠어!
You're going to forget what you've seen this time!
허니의 데이터를 초기화시키려고 하고 있어!
He's trying to reset Honey's data!
허니 기억이 없어지면 안 돼! 멈춰야 해!
I can't let him erase Honey's memory! You must stop him!
알았어!
Got it!
뭐, 뭐야?!
W- what is this?!
메타비! 블래스터!
Metabee! Use Blaster!
물론!
Right!
메타비! 구하러 와 줬구나!
Metabee! You came to rescue me!
움직이지 마!
Don't move!
이자식! 무사히 돌아갈 수 있을 거라 생각 마라!
Damn you! You aren't going back safely!
유니트리스 전송!
Transfer Unitrix!
도망치자, 허니.
Let's run away, Honey.
그, 근데, 어떻게?
B- but, how?
아, 젠장...
Er, shit...
유니트리스! 덕트 슈터!
Unitrix! Duct Shooter!
쏴, 쏴, 쏴, 쏴!
Shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot!
조심해!
Watch out!
메타비! 야, 메타비, 괜찮아?
Metabee! Hey, Metabee, are you alright?
젠장, 너무 어두워서 잘 안 보여!
Damn, it's too dark to see!
허니? 허니? 어떻게 그렇게 된 거야?
Honey? Honey? How did this happen?
나에 씨, 나, 봤어. 긴카이가...
Ms. Nae, I saw Ginkai...
허니!
Honey!
좋아!
Alright!
자, 괜찮아?
Hey, are you alright?
지금 충격으로 부유 파트가...
The shock just now damaged my floating parts...
-메타비!
-허니!
-Metabee!
-Honey!
메타비! 어이, 메타비! 메타비!
Metabee! Hey, Metabee! Metabee!
메타비!
Metabee!
에잇, 도망쳤나. 그래도 아무렴 어때. 저 꼴이라면 두 번 다시는 돌아오지 않을 테지.
They got away, eh? It doesn't matter. They're never coming back again like that.
잘 됐어.
That's good.
메타비! 메타비!
Metabee! Metabee!
메타비!
Metabee!
어두워졌으니 슬슬 돌아가야지...
It's getting dark and you should go back home.
-그래도...
-그 얘들은 내가 찾을게.
-But...
-I'll find those kids.
자, 가족이 걱정할 테니까.
You don't want to make your family worry.
미안해. 메타비까지 휘말려서...
I'm sorry for having Metabee involved in this...
어이, 정신 차려!
Hey, get a grip!
잇키! 어이, 잇키! 들려?
Ikki! Hey, Ikki! Can you hear me?
잇키! 잇키!
Ikki! Ikki!
괜찮아, 메타비라면. 분명 내일 아침에는 돌아올 거야.
Metabee will be all right. He'll come back by tomorrow morning.
아빠도 어릴 적에는 매일같이 아침에 돌아왔어. 그치?
Your dad used to come back in mornings when he was young, right?
저런, 저런!
Hey, hey!
너, 대체 어디에 있는 거야?
Where in the world are you?
뭘 하고 계십니까.
What are you doing?
이런 시간에.
In a night like this...
아, 아니...
Er, nothing...
허니...
Honey...
젠장! 안 빠져!
Damn! I can't remove this!
그건 그렇고, 여긴 어디야?
Nevermind that; what kind of place is this?
이래선 밝아질 때까지 출구는 못 찾겠어.
We're not going to find an exit until morning.
어이!
Hey!
앉아 있어. 내가 옮겨줄 테니.
Sit still. I'll carry you.
이대로 다시 나에 씨를 못 보게 되면 어떻게 해...
What if I can't go back to Ms. Nae ever again?
괜찮다니까!
Everything will work out!
그래도...
But...
어, 괜찮아! 분명 만날 수 있다니까!
It's totally fine! You'll meet her again!
-정말?
-어, 정말로 정말!
-Really?
-Yes, really really!
그러니까 그만 울어도 돼.
You don't have to cry anymore.
메타비 강하구나. 안 외로워?
You're strong, Metabee. Don't you feel lonely?
어, 나? 나는야 뭐, 아예 잇키가 없어져도 생생할 테니까 말야!
Oh, me? I'll be even livelier without Ikki!
잠깐 주변에 찾아보고 올 테니까 거기 있어.
I'll go take a look around this place, so stay there.
응.
Yeah.
잇키!
Ikki!
잇키...
Ikki...
Medarot Damashii - Subtitles by Subdiver
나에 씨!
Ms. Nae!
미안, 어젯밤에는 결국 못 찾았어. 잘 잤어?
Sorry, I couldn't find them last night. Did you have a good sleep?
응! 괜찮아!
Yeah! I'm all good!
나도.
Me too.
-자, 오늘이야말로 찾아내자.
-응.
-We will find them today.
-Right.
밝아! 어이, 출구가 보일 지도 몰라!
It's bright! Hey, we might find an exit!
응. 그래도, 나, 못 움직이는데...
Yes, but I can't move...
자. 어서 잡아. 업어줄 테니까.
Here. Hold onto me. I'll carry you.
메타비...
Metabee...
-그래도...
-괜찮아, 괜찮아! 어서 나에 씨한테 돌아가고 싶지?
-But...
It's all right, don't worry! You want to go back to Ms. Nae!
응, 고마워, 메타비!
Yes! Thank you, Metabee!
-안 무거워?
-괜찮아, 괜찮아!
-Aren't you tired?
-All good, I'm fine!
그보다도, 뭐야, 여긴?
Anyway, what is this place?
저런 곳까지 오를 수 있을 리도 없고...
There's no way we're getting up to there...
아! 메타비, 저기!
Oh! Metabee! Over there!
좋았어! 분명 어디엔가 있을 거라 생각했어!
Great! I knew it that there's an exit somewhere!
-오를 테니까 꽉 잡아!
-어.
-Hold tight while I climb up!
-Right!
해냈어!
We did it!
여, 여긴...
W- where...
어디야?!
is this place?!
여긴 고속도로 휴게소야!
You're at a service area on a highway!
왜 너희들이 여기 있는 거야!
Why are you guys even here?!
허니 몸에 발신기를 붙여 놨지.
I placed a transmitter on Honey's body.
한번은 부숴졌다고 생각했지만, 다시 발신기의 신호가 잡혔어.
I thought you two were destroyed, but I got the signal from the transmitter again.
혹시 모르니 와 본 거야.
I'm here just to be safe.
제기랄!
Damn!
-메타비, 미안해.
-바보야, 네 잘못이 아니야.
-Metabee, I'm sorry.
-Don't be stupid. It's not your fault!
이걸 어째, 나야? 어째, 메타비?
What should I do, me? What should I do, Metabee?
아! 돼지가 하늘을 난다!
Look! A flying pig!
정말?
Really?
젠장! 쫒아, 유니트리스!
Damn! Get them, Unitrix!
놓쳤냐! 뭐, 숨어도 소용없어!
Did you lose them? Doesn't matter even if they hide!
저기다!
There they are!
찾아냈구나!
He found us!
좋아, 잘 했어! 허니를 잡아!
Alright, good job! Get Honey!
놔!
Unhand her!
이게!
DAmn you!
메타비!
Metabee!
멈춰!
Stop!
엔진 시동.
Starting engine.
기어 체크 OK.
Gear check OK.
도어 록 체크.
Door lock check.
후부 체크. 잠겨 있습니다. 그대로 출발합니다.
Back side check. Locked. Departing as it is.
어, 어떻게 된 거야?
W- what's going on?
어이, 멈춰! 내 트럭!
Hey, stop! My truck!
운전수가 없어!
Nobody is driving!
달리기 시작했어!
The truck started to move!
자동 운전 스위치가 눌렸어.
Autopilot switch has been triggered.
야, 멈춰, 유니트리스!
Hey, stop, Unitrix!
-지금은 로보틀을 하고 있을 때가 아니야!
-어떤 거야? 어떤 게 바뀌었지?
-This is not a good time to be Robattling!
-What is it? What has changed?
큰일이야! 부숴졌어!
This is bad! It's broken!
이게! 멈춰! 멈춰!
Damn you! Stop! Stop the truck!
유니트리스! 트럭을 멈춰!
Unitrix! Stop the truck!
커맨드 에러. 그 명령은 프로그램되어 있지 않습니다.
Command error. That command isn't programmed.
커맨드를 다시 입력해 주십시오.
Please input a recognizable command.
뭐라고?
What?
어이! 트럭을 멈춰! 멈추라고!
Hey! Stop the truck! Stop the damn thing!
-어이, 멈춰! 그만해!
-핸들!
-Hey, stop! Stop it!
-The handle!
멈춰! 멈추라니까! 이게 뭐라고 못 한다는 거야!
Stop! I told you to stop! Why is this so difficult for you?!
그렇구나. 싸움만을 위해 개발된 데스 메다로트는 로보틀 이외의 명령은 못 알아먹는다는 거구나!
I see. Death Medarots are really only for fighting, so that it can't comprehend any command other than that!
이 쓸모없는 것!
You useless thing!
마을 맨홀이란 맨홀은 죄다,
We've looked all manholes in the village,
하수도라는 하수도는 죄다 찾았는데 못 찾다니.
and all the sewers, and we couldn't find them.
설마 바다까지 흘러간 게...
Could it be that they drifted to the sea?
그럴 리가.
No way.
긴급 교통 정보를 보내 드립니다. 현재 제 8 고속도로에 트럭이 폭주하고 있습니다.
Emergency traffic information. Currently, a truck is road raging on the 8th highway.
관련 도로는 전부 폐쇄되었고, 3km 이내에는 정체가 극심합니다.
All the associated roads are closed, and it is very congested in 3km radius.
각자 도로 상황을 확인해서 우회해 주십시오.
Please refer to the traffic and take a detour.
-왜 그래, 나에 씨?
-What's wrong, Ms. Nae?
-이, 이거, 이거!
-반복합니다.
-T- this, this!
-Repeat.
현재 제 8 고속도로에 트럭이...
Currently, a truck is road raging...
-메타비!
-허니!
-Metabee!
-Honey!
어떻게 이렇게 된 거야! 정말!
How did this even happen?! Really!
틀렸어... 누가 살려줘!
I'm doomed... Someone save me!
가만히 있으랬잖아! 이게!
I told you to stay off! Get off!
이게!
Get lost!
허니! 핸들을 힘껏 돌려!
Honey! Turn the handle as much as you can!
제기랄!
Damn!
누가 살려줘!
Someone help me!
긴카이!
Ginkai!
사, 살려줘!
H- help me!
잠깐만. 지금 구해줄 테니까.
Wait. We're going to save you right now.
뭘 하고 있어? 어서 브레이크를 밟아!
What are you doing? Step on the brake!
자동 운전 때문에 브레이크가 말을 안 들어!
Brake isn't working because of the autopilot!
-뭐라고?
-어떻게 해야 해, 나에 씨?!
-What?!
-What should we do, Ms. Nae?!
하나 방법이 있어.
There's one thing you can do.
트럭 아래로 기어가서 컴퓨터하고 엔진을 잇는 파트를 파괴해.
Go down the truck and destroy the connector between computer and engine.
그래도 저 속도로는 너무 위험해. 무리야.
But it's too dangerous with that speed. It's impossible.
무리인지 아닌지는 해보지 않으면 모르지! 그 밖에 방법이 없다면 난 할 거야!
You don't know what's impossible if you don't try! If that's the only thing I can do, then I'll do that!
메타비.
Metabee.
좋아! 부탁해, 메타비!
Alright! It's up to you, Metabee!
맡겨 둬!
Leave it to me!
조심해, 메타비!
Be careful, Metabee!
어디야, 나에 씨!
Where is it, Ms. Nae?!
조금 더 위. 아, 너무 갔어. 거기서 오른쪽.
Go upper. No, not that much. A bit to the right.
그거야! 그 하얀 상자야.
That's it! That white box is it.
어, 어째... 이대로는 들이박겠어!
W- what should I do? We're gonna crash at this rate!
이거야!
This is it!
어이! 막다른 길이야!
Hey! You're heading to a dead end!
괜찮아, 메타비!?
Are you alright, Metabee!?
허니, 거긴 막다른 길이야!
Honey, that way is to a dead end!
그래도...
But still...
서둘러, 메타비!
Hurry, Metabee!
메타비! 다시 한번! 힘내!
Metabee! Do it again! You can do it!
이번이야말로!
I got you this time!
해냈어!
You did it!
아직이야. 길이 더는 없어!
Not yet. There's no more road!
제발! 멈춰!
Please! Stop!
젠장, 멈춰, 멈춰!
Damn! Stop! Stop moving!
멈춰 줘!
Please stop!
메타비!
Metabee!
잇키!
Ikki!
구려, 너, 우웩...
You stink!
너, 감동의 재회에서 처음 하는 말이라는 게 그거냐! 하룻밤 수도에 있었으니 어쩔 수 없잖아!
Did you have to say that as your first word of the reunion?! I spent a night in sewers and of course I smell!
저기, 구해줘서 고마워. 허니 가져가서 미안해.
Er, thank you for saving me. I'm sorry for taking Honey.
그렇네, 허니가 뭘 봤는지 알려주면 용서해 줄게.
Oh well, I guess I'm forgiving you if Honey tells me what did she see.
허니, 보여 줘.
Honey, show us.
그것만은!
Anything but that!
너무했어, 너무해!
That was too much!
-다로메트 7 데이터를 지웠다니!
-미안하다니까.
-You erased my save data for Daromet 7!
-I told you I'm sorry!
-울지 마.
-기껏 코쿠류에게...
-Don't cry.
-Right when I finally got an e-mail
-코스모스를 쓰러트리는 방법을 메일 받았는데...
-아, 그래, 미안미안. 다시 열심히 하면 되잖아? 그만 울어.
-about how to take Cosmos down from Kokuryu...
-Yeah, sure, I'm sorry, but you can do that again! Stop crying.
돌아가서 수리나 해야지.
I'm going back and repairing.
나 목욕이나 할래.
I'm going for a bath.
숙제 있었나?
Did I have a homework?
근데 말야, 이거 어쩌냐!
But anyway, what should we do about this?!
형 또 운다.
Brother's crying again!
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
이와노이와의 로보틀에서 믿기지 않는 3연패를 기록한 카가미야마.
Kagamiya unbelievably lost 3 times in a row Robattles with Iwanoi.
책임을 느낀 키스터틀. 카가미야마의 옆을 떠나 마을을 떠돌다 닿은 곳에서 그가 본 것.
Kiethturtle felt responsible for this. He parted from Kagamiyama, wandered, and finally reached somewhere.
그것은 마스터에게 버려진 메다로트들이었다.
What he saw were Medarots abandoned by their masters.
돌연 그들은 일어나서 키스터틀에게 덤빈다.
They suddenly stood up and charged against Kiethturtle.
과연 잇키와 메타비는 키스터틀을 구해낼 수 있을 것인가?
Will Ikki and Metabee manage to rescue Kiethturtle?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 메다로트 묘지
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Medarot Cemetery
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!